Hiring Manager April 14, 2022

CITY OF TORONTO 55 JOHN ST. TORONTO, ONTARIO

Job Application for an Engineer in Training

Dear Hiring Manager,

Good afternoon, I am writing in response to your posting for a Engineer in Training (ID 26385). I am an EIT, currently employed at Ontario Clean Water Agency in the region of Kitchener/Waterloo as a Maintenance Management Specialist.

I have recently completed my Master's of Science at Ryerson University for Chemical Engineering, where I researched *chemical reactor engineering*. I have studied and designed water and wastewater treatment technologies for over 3 years. My primary focus is the application of bioreactors for biological nutrient removal. My research has required the operation and a design of multiple research studies.

In my current role of Asset Maintenance Specialist, I've had the opportunity to work on multiple Capital Projects. I have written Request for Bids (RFB) for multiple projects, including the resurfacing of roofs for about 20 different facilities within the region of Waterloo. I have also taken part in tenure evaluations, the latest being for Flow Meter calibration and verification. I have completed my Project Management contact hours, and I am currently a PMI member.

I have a strong background in Data Science supported by multiple certificates. I am proficient in Excel, Google Sheets, MS Access, SQL, the R programming language, Python and many more. I have also worked in multiple Computerized Maintenance Management Systems (CMMS) as a maintenance planner.

I would like to thank you for your time and for your considerations. I look forward to hearing back from you. Please feel free to call me at (647) 400-4679 or email me at m2edney@gmail.com

Sincerely,

Mark Edney



□ (647) 400-4679 | ■ m2edney@gmail.com | □ mark-edney | □ edneymark

Researched Water and Wastewater treatment technologies for over 3 years. Employed in the water treatment industry for another 3 years in the capacity of an Asset Management Specialist/Project Manager.

Summary_

- MaSC in Chemical Engineering (Ryerson)
 Engineer in Training (PEO)

PMI Member

Data Scientist

Education

Masters of Science in Chemical Engineering

Toronto - Ontario 2018 - 2020

RYERSON UNIVERSITY

• Master's Thesis: Investigation of the Flow Dynamics of a Vertical Bioreactor using the Residence Time Distribution

- Presented research at the 69th Canadian Chemical Engineering Conference in Halifax, NS
- Wrote professional level reports for thesis and different coursework
- Related course work: Advanced process control (CE 8202), Decentralized waste water treatment technologies (CE 8702), Advanced Modeling Techniques (CE8204), Advanced Reactor Engineering (CE8403) and Modelling and Simulation (CE8201)

Bachelor of Engineering Chemical Engineering (Co-op)

Toronto - Ontario

RYERSON UNIVERSITY

2006 - 2011

- · Capstone Project: Design of Biological Nutrient Removal (BNR) watewater treatment plant for a meatpacking plant
- · Related course work: Law and Ethics, Water and Wastewater Treatment, Air Pollution and Control, Process and Engineering Optimization, Process Control

Employment

Asset Maintenance Specialist

Kitchener - Ontario

ONTARIO CLEAN WATER AGENCY

Jun. 2021 - Present

- · Participated in Capital Projects including: writing Request for Services (RFS), evaluating bids and act as liaison for service providers
- Act as data owner for the region of Waterloo's wastewater computerized maintenance management system
- Built reports and dashboards with engaging visualizations with Power BI
- Incorporate Kanban principles (Trello) into department workflow

Graduate Assistant/Researcher

Toronto - Ontario"

RYERSON UNIVERSITY

Sept. 2018 - Oct. 2020

- Assistant for following classes: CHE204, CHE214, CHE215, CHE426, CHE615, CHE616
- Marked Co-op term reports by utilizing time management skills to complete on schedule without interrupting experiment/research activities
- · Studied the behaviour of a novel vertical bioreactor in water engineering, applying chemical reactor engineering techniques (Thesis)
- · Invigilated examinations to uphold academic integrity within Ryerson University

Quality Assurance Technician

Mississauga - Ontario

WAL-MART LOGISTICS CANADA

July 2014 - June 2021

- Perform frequent Quality Assurance checks on merchandise received from suppliers
- · Corrected quality assurance mistakes by following standard operating procedures to create a more accurate warehouse database
- · Coach new employees by clearly communicating my years of knowledge and experience to reduce errors and increase productivity

Asset Management Specialist (Project Manager)

Mississauga - Ontario

ONTARIO CLEAN WATER AGENCY

Dec. 2011 - Feb. 2013

- Part of project management team to add value to our customers
- Created preventative maintenance management plans as a deliverable
- Wrote professional standard operating procedures for maintenance activities
- Performed audits on computerized databases
- Spearheaded a project for the city of London and Cambridge for two new sludge treatment facilities
- Modernized the South Peel Computerized Maintenance Management System (C.M.M.S) with supplemental information from professional resources (P&ID drawings and O & M manuals)

MARK EDNEY · RÉSUMÉ APRIL 14, 2022



Programming Languages Python, R, Matlab

Visualizations Tableau, Power BI, GGplot2

Markup LanguagesCSS, HTML, Latex, Markdown, RMarkdownMicrosoft OfficeExcel, Outlook, OneNote, PowerPoint, Visio, Word

Certifications

Deep Learning Specialization

Coursera: DeepLearning.Al January, 2022

- Neural Networks, Convolutional Neural Networks, Sequence Models
- Structuring Machine Learning Projects

Google Data Analytics

COURSERA: GOOGLE August, 2021

- Foundations of Data Analytics
- SQL, R, Tableau

Data Science Specialization

COURSERA: JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY

May, 2021

• R, Git

Professional Practice Examination

Professional Engineers of Ontario

August, 2018

Certified Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt

GO LEAN SIX SIGMA August, 2018

Excel with Macros and VBA Record of Achievement

GEORGE BROWN COLLEGE June, 2017

AutoCAD Fundamentals

GEORGE BROWN COLLEGE

June, 2017

- Advanced 2D
- Introduction to 3D

PMP Exam Prep Course (35 contact hours)

PMCampus November, 2015

Affiliations

Professional Engineers of Ontario

ENGINEER IN TRAINING

Canadian Society of Chemical Engineers

MEMBER

Ontario Society of Professional Engineers

MEMBER

Project Management Institute

Member

Ryerson Tri-Mentoring Program

MENTOR